Jason Ng

🔭 jasonkng.dev 🛚 in jasonkngdev 🔀 jasonkngdev@gmail.com 👂 New York, NY

PROFILE

I'm a full-stack software engineer with experience in JavaScript/Node.js, Ruby, React, PostgreSQL, as well as Docker and Infrastructure-as-Code deployments using AWS. Most recently, I built Canopy, an open-source real-time monitoring framework for CDN logs and metrics with automated deployment to AWS.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Co-Creator, Canopy, (canopy-framework.github.io) &

04/2023 - present

- Researched, architected and built a streaming ETL pipeline for centralizing Amazon CloudFront CDN logs and visualizing generated metrics on real-time dashboards
- Reduced buffering latency to a customizable amount (as low as 0 seconds) by engineering a custom solution for delivering real-time streaming data using AWS Lambda
- Implemented a buffer for re-streaming and retrying failed logs using AWS Lambda and Kinesis Data Streams, as well as a dead-letter queue using AWS SQS for routing failed logs to persistent storage
- Containerized and configured backend services, including Vector, ClickHouse and Grafana using Docker Compose
- Implemented native support for monitoring parallel CloudFront distributions by automating their attachment and detachment to and from the pipeline, while tracking their meta-data with SQLite
- Automated 50+ AWS steps down to a single deploy command, by writing CDK code to deploy two CloudFormation stacks
- Created a CLI to facilitate configuration, deployment, and teardown of the pipeline
- Built an Admin Dashboard with React and Material UI so users can monitor pipeline status and configure alerts
- Set up email notifications to minimize incident response time
- Authored a case study on Canopy's problem domain, architecture, challenges and design decisions (canopy-framework.github.io ∂)

Software Engineer, Self-Employed

11/2022 - 04/2023

- Developed open-source web applications using Node.js, Express, Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, React, HTML, and CSS. Projects include:
 - Request Warehouse: a real-time tool for receiving and monitoring webhooks (Node.js/Express, React, Material UI, MongoDB, Webhooks, DigitalOcean Droplet, NGINX)
 - Done & Done: an interactive to-do list manager (Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS)

Futures Trader, Self-Employed

01/2011 - 12/2022

• Executed split-second decisions for trading index futures, based on technical analysis of volatility chart patterns, order flow, momentum of price movement and market conditions.

SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Express, Jest, Ruby, Sinatra, SQL, HTML, CSS

Cloud

AWS: CDK, SDK, EC2, ECS, Fargate, IAM, Lambda, CloudFormation, S3, SQS; Digital Ocean Droplets; Heroku

Other Technologies

Git, GitHub, Node.js, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Unit Testing, RESTful APIs, Bash, Docker, Webhooks, SQLite

EDUCATION

Launch School, Software Engineering & Full Stack Development

Multi-year full-stack software engineering curriculum with mastery-based learning

11/2022 - 04/2023